Guide to the Diya Records, 1992-2006
Duke University. University Archives
Diya records 1992-2006
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Diya.
4.8 linear feet Extent: 3400 Items
Diya supports the cultural, social, and political development of South Asian and South Asian-American students. Contains the records of the Diya, the South Asian American Association of Duke University, from 1995-2001. Types of materials include a short history, agendas, minutes, budgets, correspondence, a constitution, events reports, election materials, and programs. Major subjects include South Asian students at Duke University, South Asian-American students at Duke University, student group governance, South Asian culture, and South Asian-American culture. Diya is a member of Spectrum, an intercultural coalition of student leaders and organizations at Duke University.
UA.31.04.0001
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
No Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Location Section 25
Provenance
The Diya Records were received by the University Archives as transfers in 2001 and 2006.
Historical Note
From Diya's web site: http://www.duke.edu/web/diya/about.html
Diya, founded in 1986, is Duke University's largest South Asian-American student organization. The group strives to provide a forum for interaction among those interested in South Asian heritage and South Asian-American culture. Diya promotes the sharing of these cultures with the Duke community and represents South Asian and South Asian-American interests to the campus at large. One of the ways Diya seeks to increase university-wide exposure beyond the scope of the South Asian community is through cultural programming. The most important of Diya's cultural events is AWAAZ, which takes place around, Diwali, the Festival of Lights in India. Some of Diya's other programming include South Asia Week, Holi Celebration, community service projects, discussions, teach-ins, and mixers with other South Asian student groups in North Carolina.
Diya is part of Spectrum, a unifying organization at Duke University for historically under-represented groups. Other South Asian student groups on-campus are AID India and the Hindu Students Council.
Collection Overview
Contains printed e-mail correspondence, election information, fliers, agendas, minutes, newsletters, a budget, event reports, and constitution pertaining to Diya, the South Asian-American Association of Duke University, as well as scrapbooks, photo albums, photographs, negatives, VHS cassette video recordings, CD-RW, and CD-R sound recordings from 1992 to 2006.
Subject Headings
Duke University. Diya; Duke University -- History; Duke University. Spectrum; Duke University -- Students; Duke University -- Students -- Social conditions; South Asian Americans -- Ethnic identity; South Asian Americans -- Race identity; South Asian Americans -- Social conditions; South Asian Americans -- Social life and customs; South Asian Americans -- North Carolina -- Durham; South Asians -- United States -- North Carolina -- Durham; South Asians -- United States -- Social conditions
Related Material
Asian Students Association Records.
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Printed Material, 1995-2001
  - Budgets, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (printed e-mail), newsgroup announcements, 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Diya constitution, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diwali and other events, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Election materials, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Event reports, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Executive board meeting agendas, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Executive board meeting minutes, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter, Diyalogue, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Spectrum constitution, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - News Clippings, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Audiovisual Material,1997-2001
  - Photograph Album, 1997-1998, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Photograph Album, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Photograph Album, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Photograph Album, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - Photograph Album, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - Photograph Album, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous photographs of Diya events, undated (Box 2)
  - Awaaz, undated (Box 3)
  - Awaaz, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Awaaz, copies 1 and 2 2002 (Box 3)
  - CD Disk 1 Ek Pal Ka Jenna, Diwali, 2000 (Box 3)
  - CD Disk 2 Finale, undated (Box 3)
  - CD Disk 3 Ek Pal Ka Jenna, Diwali, 2000 (Box 3)
- Notebooks,1992-2006
  - Executive Council Notebook, 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Executive Council Notebook, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Archives, includes constitution, minutes, agendas and miscellaneous material, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Executive Council Notebook, 2003-2004 (Box 5)
  - Executive Council Notebook, 2004-2005 (Box 5)
  - Executive Council Notebook, 2005-2006 (Box 5)
  - Minutes, Agendas, Notices, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - International Festival Notebook, 1995 April 8 (Box 5)